ikeafamilylivemagazine.com 2015-06-08

# IKEA UK Privacy Policy

**live IS BROUGHT TO YOU BY:** live EDITOR **Lotta Brandt** INTERNATIONAL CREATIVE DIRECTOR **Jules Rogers** INTERNATIONAL EDITOR **Helen Bazuaye** FEATURES EDITOR **Ellie Fazan** FEATURES ASSISTANT **Kate Herbert-Smith** HOUSES EDITOR **Bethan John** Product/Shoot Co-ordinator **Annie Towers** CHIEF SUB EDITOR **Kate Britten** DEPUTY CHIEF SUB EDITOR **Caroline Drew** SUB EDITORS **Naomi Misquita-Rice** , **Saskia Liebenberg** ART EDITOR **Sam Franks** DESIGNER **Mella McKeown** PICTURE EDITORS **Giulia Galati** , **Clare Limpus** Senior Artworker **David Sharman** Junior artworker **Stella Ajao** INTERNATIONAL EDITORIAL DIRECTOR **Sarah Bravo** MANAGING DIRECTOR **Mark Lonergan** SEE MORE HOMES & IDEAS FROM IKEA FAMILY at IKEAFAMILYLIVE.COM

 **DIGITAL TEAM: Katy Davis, Lucy Hatherall, Helen Brown, Paul Hamilton** FOR IKEA **Hiral Ramaiya** ADVERTISING SALES MANAGER **Ciara McGettrick** 020 7033 0931 DESIGN & PRODUCTION **August Media Ltd, Zetland House, Scrutton Street, London, EC2A 4HJ, UK, TEL 020 7749 3300,** EMAIL **info@augustmedia.com**

 ****Reproduction in whole or part is strictly forbidden. The opinions expressed in this publication are those of the authors or persons interviewed only and do not necessarily reflect the views of IKEA or August Media. All prices are maximum prices valid until 21 July 2013 (Prices are subject to any alteration in VAT)

### A partnership in trust

When IKEA set out to create a high-quality, low-priced line of home furnishings, we knew we couldn’t do it without the help of some very important partners - you, our customers. Whether you’re ordering goods online through the IKEA website, picking up your furniture in our self-serve warehouses or assembling your purchases at home - we’re working together to help you create a better everyday life at a price everyone can afford. IKEA is based on a partnership with our customers. Without you, IKEA could not exist.

This partnership extends to the way we handle your personal information. Just as shopping at IKEA is a co-operative experience, IKEA makes a point of working with our customers when it comes to their privacy. This Privacy Notice is our way of telling you what information we collect, how we use it, who we will disclose it to and how you can access, change and remove your information.

### Help us build a better IKEA

In order to create a better IKEA, we need your help. You can help by providing us with various kinds of information to help IKEA serve you better, and ultimately improve IKEA for everyone. Below you’ll find an explanation of some of the reasons we request information from you, as well as some details about how we obtain and use that information.

Throughout this Privacy Notice where we refer to your "personal information" what we mean by this is any information you provide to us about you including your name, postal address, email address and telephone number.

## Where we collect your personal information

### Catalogue

If you ask us to mail you an IKEA catalogue, we need your name and address. We also ask for your telephone number and email address in case there are any problems with delivery. You also have the option of providing us with additional information about products that interest you and other lifestyle information. Why do we ask for this additional information? It helps us learn about the people who shop at IKEA so we can better tailor our products, stores and website to you. Of course, providing this additional information is purely optional.

### Purchases

When you make a purchase through our website, you will need to give us your credit or debit card number and other personal information. This information is necessary in order to process your payment and make delivery of your goods.

### Customer service

In order for a customer service representative to respond to your questions or concerns, we may need personal information like your name, address and telephone number. This information is used to answer your questions as completely and thoroughly as possible.

### Special offers, promotions, coupons and warranties

When you register for or redeem IKEA special offers, discount coupons or other promotions, we may ask for personal information in order to note the success of our promotions for future offers. You may also provide such personal information when you fill out a warranty card about a product you purchased from IKEA. Or you may provide us with personal information such as product preferences, reasons for purchasing a product, or family and lifestyle information to help us learn more about your shopping preferences.

No matter what we collect your personal information for, we promise only to use it in the ways set out in this Privacy Notice. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us processing this personal information in one or more of the ways described in this Privacy Notice.

## Information that we collect automatically

IKEA use technology commonly called “cookies” to manage our website and to ensure that it can carry out the functions that you expect when you visit. Cookies are small files sent by us to your computer which we can refer to later, they can be in the form of session or persistent cookies and may use different technologies such as JavaScript or Flash. Cookies help us make your experience of using our website smooth and as relevant to you as possible. They show us what you and other users do on our website, which helps us make the whole experience better for everyone. You will find more information on how we use cookies we use [here](http://www.ikea.com/ms/en_GB/privacy_policy/cookie_policy.html "Click here").

There are different types of cookie in use:

• Strictly necessary cookies are used to enable the services you have requested such as online checkout retrieval of your IKEA profile information.

• Performance cookies collect anonymous information on which pages you visit, this can tell us which products are most popular and how customers move through our website.

• Functional cookies are used to remember choices that you made and thereby further enhance your experience. For example, if you tell us which store you prefer and that you don’t like to be contacted via SMS we will remember.

• Targeting cookies allow you to share information and send information to other websites that may be relevant to you.

We may access cookies stored on your computer when you visit our site in future or when you open an email from us.

If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to your browser manufacturer’s instructions by clicking “Help” in your browser menu. Please note that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access or use certain areas or features of our site

## What we will do with your information

What you share with IKEA stays with IKEA 

We hate spam just as much as you do. So we promise never to sell your personal information to any unconnected third parties.

On occasion, we do need to hire other companies to help us provide some services. In some of these cases we may need to share information that these companies need, in order to provide services to us and ultimately to you. For example, a delivery service will need to know your name and address in order to deliver your goods to you. Other services provided by different companies may include providing marketing assistance, processing credit/debit card payments and providing customer services. We'll limit the personal information we give them, and they will only have access to your personal information for the purposes of performing such functions. They are strictly monitored by IKEA in order to make certain our customers' privacy is always protected.

In proceeding with your online order, you agree that both your name and postal address and those of the delivery name and address (if different) will be checked using third parties such as credit agencies. If you are providing a delivery name and address which is not your own you must have that person's permission to give us their personal information and for us to use it for the purposes specified, by providing it you are saying you have their permission.  
 **N.B. the transfer of financial data is always via a secure network.**

At times, some of your personal information may be transferred to IKEA divisions in other countries but we always maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorised disclosure, use, alteration and destruction of the information in our possession.

In assessing an application for credit, to prevent fraud, to check your identity and to prevent money laundering, IKEA or IKANO (a company who IKEA use to carry out such searches) may search the files of credit reference agencies who will record any credit searches under your name. We may also disclose details of how you conduct your account to such agencies. This information will be used by other credit grantors for making credit decisions about you and the people with whom you are financially associated, for fraud prevention, money laundering prevention and occasionally for tracing debtors. Information used for these purposes will include publicly available information such as electoral roll, county court judgments, bankruptcy orders or repossessions.

We may disclose your personal information in order to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation, such as a request by the police. We may also transfer your personal information in the event that our business (or part of it) is sold, and the purchaser needs your personal information to carry on providing services.

## Marketing

If you provide any personal information to us you give us permission to contact you for marketing purposes, which may include messages via post, telephone, SMS or email.

We'll make sure that we only send you messages that we think will be of interest to you – for instance the dates of our in-store and online sales, details of special offers or information about new products and services. If you do not want us to use your personal information to market to you, you can decide to opt-out of these types of marketing messages at any time by changing the settings in your Profile or by following the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email we send to you.

## Storing your information and keeping it up to date

### Out of sight, but never out of reach

When you share your personal information with IKEA, you will always have access to this information. Where you store a "Profile" on the website, you can amend the details stored in your account yourself. Alternatively, you can update, change or remove any personal information at any time by calling, writing or emailing us using one of the options provided below.

If you want to find out what personal information IKEA holds about you, please write to our Data Protection Officer at the postal address given below. We may charge you a small fee for providing this information.

### Keeping it safe

We are committed to providing appropriate security controls to protect your personal information against foreseeable hazards. Making sure that your personal information is secure is very important to IKEA. For more details please visit our Security Section.

### Change of address? Change of heart? Let us know

If you would like us to update your personal information, remove your name from our mailing list, or if you have any questions about IKEA’s privacy policies or your personal information, please don’t hesitate to contact us.

Call IKEA Customer Services on 0845 358 3363

Write to us at:  
IKEA Customer Relations   
Kingston Park  
Fletton   
Peterborough   
PE2 9ET

Registered office: IKEA Limited, 21 Holborn Viaduct, London, EC1A 2DY

We will respond to your questions or concerns as quickly as possible.

 **Occasionally, we may decide to change this Privacy Notice so we suggest that you review it periodically so you are aware of any changes.**
